MICHAEL A. PALERMO

√ 708.940.2779 |

✓ michaelpalermooo@gmail.com |

† Westchester, IL

LinkedIn | Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Front-end engineer with 4+ years of experience building performant, intuitive user interfaces using modern technologies including React, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, and REST APIs. Secret Clearance for DOD and limited BI for DHS in the process of obtaining Public Trust with additional financial requirements for CBP.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C#, Go, SQL

Cloud/DevOps: AWS (Lambda, S3, API Gateway, CloudFront, Route53, CloudWatch, Kinesis),

GitLab CI/CD, Docker

Frameworks: Spring Boot, React, Angular, Next.js Databases: MySQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL

Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Jira, Confluence, Postman, Jest

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer

Ellumen, Inc | DHS/CBP Contract | Remote | Dec 2023 – Present

- Independently led delivery of new React features for Homeland Security websites under federal compliance standards
- Obtained a limited BI Clearance, in the process of getting Full Public Trust Clearance
- Collaborated cross-functionally with stakeholders, designers, and engineers to ship production-ready UI
- Setup custom Al chatbot using Kommunicate for FAQ ease of use

AWS Cloud Engineer

Ellumen, Inc | DOD Contract | Remote | Mar 2023 – Dec 2023

- Designed and deployed serverless AWS applications with Lambda
- Built robust REST APIs using AWS API Gateway and improved system observability via custom monitoring solutions
- Contributed to implementation of automated Jest Unit tests (85%+ coverage) and CI/CD pipelines, reducing release cycles from 1 week to 1 day
- Wrote custom backend Java code to fix file export feature, splitting attachment files into more manageable chunks (From 49 mb to 10mb for example)

Full Stack Software Developer

LabCorp Drug Development | Clinical Trial Software Company | Remote | Sep 2021 - Dec 2022

- Deployed iOS and Android apps for clinical study companies like Johnson & Johnson and Pfizer
- Participated in agile ceremonies and actively contributed to architecture and documentation standards
- Developed scalable backend services using Java as part of the SnapClinical platform
- Created secure auth workflows and designed Flowable BPMN processes

SQL Developer

Thatcher Technology Group | Direct Selling Software Company | Naperville, IL | Feb 2021 – Aug 2021

- Optimized large-scale SQL Server gueries, increasing performance by 30%
- Supported .NET development and Spring Boot microservice enhancements
- Handled deployments and live upgrades, maintaining near-perfect system uptime

Software Development Intern

ComEd | Oakbrook Terrace, IL | Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Created Alexa Smart Home Skills using AWS Lambda and Node.js
- Presented final results to 100+ executives

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science – Computer Engineering

Lewis University | Romeoville, IL | 2016 – 2020

- GPA: 3.74 | Minors: Mathematics & Computer Science
- Dean's List All Semesters | Fitzpatrick Scholarship Recipient